epip.org 2013-09-05

# Privacy policy :: Emerging Practitioners in Philanthropy

Last Updated: March 2012

The policies below are applicable to the Web site located at [epip.org](http://www.epip.org/), which is maintained by Emerging Practitioners in Philanthropy (EPIP), a project of the Tides Center. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our Web site. They do not apply to information that you may submit to us offline or to Web sites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link.

By visiting our Web site, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Web site.

EPIP collects personal information, voluntarily submitted by visitors to the Web site, which enables us to respond to requests for publications, distribute e-newsletters, and respond to requests for more information or assistance. EPIP adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Web site. Except as disclosed below, we don’t sell, barter, give away, rent or permit anyone outside of EPIP to use your personal information.

We occasionally use third-party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners to perform functions such as marketing, analytics, etc., on our behalf. These entities have access to the personal information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of any personal information collected from the Web site. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Web site.

We may also use or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Web site; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Web site or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents or the users of the Web site or the public.

EPIP also collects anonymous information to help us tailor the Web site to visitor interests and concerns. We use “cookies” to help us understand which parts of our Web site are the most popular, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. The information that is gathered through cookies is used solely to assist in improving Web site design and function. This Web site is functional without the retention of cookies. You may elect to block cookies from this site through your browser settings.

EPIP strives to protect the transmission of any information submitted by visitors. But no transmission of data is completely secure, and submissions are at the visitor’s risk.

This Web site may contain links to sites operated by third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information gathered through these other Web sites.

Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as comments areas or feedback sections, may become public, and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. Please be careful about what you disclose, and do not post any personal information that you expect to keep private.

The Web site is published in the United States and is subject to laws of the United States. If you are located in a country outside the United States and voluntarily submit personal information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the United States. EPIP shall not be liable under any circumstances for damages resulting from use of information collected from visitors to the site.

Text, photos, graphics and other materials found on this Web site are property of EPIP or in the public domain except as noted on this Web site.

Materials may be reproduced only in their entirety and only for noncommercial, educational or personal purposes. Reproduction in part or for other purposes requires EPIP’s prior written consent.

Reproduction of Materials licensed by EPIP also requires the consent of the licensor.

EPIP may change this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in the way we collect visitor information.

If you have questions or comments, please contact us.
